export const chapter = "Chapter - 13: OUR ENVIRONMENT ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
        {
          question: "What is the environment composed of?",
          optionA: "Water, electricity, and air",
          optionB:
            "Water, plants, animals, air, soil, and other natural things",
          optionC: "Cars, buildings, and plastic bags",
          correctAnswer:
            "Water, plants, animals, air, soil, and other natural things",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Why is a clean environment necessary for a peaceful and healthy life?",
          optionA: "It makes the surroundings look nice",
          optionB: "It helps in the existence of life on earth",
          optionC: "It is a trend to live in a clean environment",
          correctAnswer: "It helps in the existence of life on earth",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What are some factors that cause harm to the environment, as mentioned in the text?",
          optionA: "Planting trees and using jute bags",
          optionB:
            "Cutting of trees, misuse of electricity, and open dumping of garbage",
          optionC: "Recycling paper and avoiding polythene bags",
          correctAnswer:
            "Cutting of trees, misuse of electricity, and open dumping of garbage",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How can individuals contribute to saving the environment, according to the text?",
          optionA: "Use more polythene bags for convenience",
          optionB: "Burn garbage to dispose of it",
          optionC:
            "Plant trees, use eco-friendly bags, conserve water, and avoid wasting electricity",
          correctAnswer:
            "Plant trees, use eco-friendly bags, conserve water, and avoid wasting electricity",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is one way to care for the environment mentioned in the text?",
          optionA: "Use polythene bags for shopping",
          optionB: "Step on plants to make them grow better",
          optionC: "Throw wrappers, polybags, cartons, etc. in the dustbin",
          correctAnswer:
            "Throw wrappers, polybags, cartons, etc. in the dustbin",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What should you do with leftover water, according to the text?",
          optionA: "Pour it down the drain",
          optionB: "Use it to water the plants",
          optionC: "Drink it to avoid wasting",
          correctAnswer: "Use it to water the plants",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which of the following is NOT mentioned as a factor causing harm to the environment?",
          optionA: "Cutting of trees",
          optionB: "Planting more trees",
          optionC: "Dirty water from homes and industries",
          correctAnswer: "Planting more trees",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is suggested for birds in the text as a way to contribute to the environment?",
          optionA: "Planting more trees",
          optionB: "Putting water pots for birds on your terrace",
          optionC: "Using polythene bags",
          correctAnswer: "Putting water pots for birds on your terrace",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Why is burning garbage considered harmful to the environment?",
          optionA: "It produces pleasant smells",
          optionB: "It releases harmful pollutants into the air",
          optionC: "It is a quick and efficient method of disposal",
          correctAnswer: "It releases harmful pollutants into the air",
        },
        {
          question:
            "According to the text, what do small steps taken by individuals contribute to?",
          optionA: "Making the environment dirtier",
          optionB:
            "Protecting the environment and making the earth a beautiful place to live",
          optionC: "No impact on the environment",
          correctAnswer:
            "Protecting the environment and making the earth a beautiful place to live",
        },
      ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
        {
          question:
            "A clean environment is necessary to live a _________ and healthy life.",
          options: ["Noisy", "Peaceful", "Crowded"],
          correctAnswer: "Peaceful",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The environment consists of water, plants, animals, air, soil, and all the other _________ things.",
          options: ["Synthetic", "Man-made", "Natural"],
          correctAnswer: "Natural",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Dirty water from homes and industries is one of the factors that cause harm to our _________.",
          options: ["Economy", "Environment", "Education"],
          correctAnswer: "Environment",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Individuals can contribute to saving the environment by planting trees, using eco-friendly bags, conserving water, and avoiding wasting _________.",
          options: ["Electricity", "Time", "Money"],
          correctAnswer: "Electricity",
        },
        {
          question:
            "It is suggested in the text to throw wrappers, polybags, cartons, etc. in the _________.",
          options: ["Air", "Dustbin", "Water"],
          correctAnswer: "Dustbin",
        },
        {
          question:
            "According to the text, one way to care for the environment is to use leftover water to _________ the plants.",
          options: ["Feed", "Water", "Wash"],
          correctAnswer: "Water",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Burning garbage is considered harmful because it releases _________ pollutants into the air.",
          options: ["Pleasant", "Harmful", "Colorful"],
          correctAnswer: "Harmful",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Small steps taken by individuals can contribute to protecting the environment and making the earth a _________ place to live.",
          options: ["Dangerous", "Dirty", "Beautiful"],
          correctAnswer: "Beautiful",
        },
        {
          question:
            "According to the text, what should individuals avoid tearing for fun?",
          options: ["Clothes", "Papers", "Plastic"],
          correctAnswer: "Papers",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The text suggests putting water pots for birds on your terrace as a way to contribute to the _________.",
          options: ["Economy", "Environment", "Entertainment"],
          correctAnswer: "Environment",
        },
      ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
        {
          question: "Independence Day is celebrated on 15th August every year.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "On Republic Day, the main function is held at India Gate in Delhi.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Gandhi Jayanti is celebrated on 2nd October every year to mark the birthday of Jawaharlal Nehru.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Mahatma Gandhi is considered as the father of the nation and played a great role in motivating people to struggle for wealth.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "On Gandhi Jayanti, people pay homage to Gandhiji at Rajghat, the Samadhi of Mahatma Gandhi in Delhi.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Independence Day is celebrated in every school, college, and other organizations with great silence.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The President of India unfurls the National Flag on Republic Day.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "On Independence Day, our Prime Minister hoists the National Flag at India Gate in Delhi and addresses the nation.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The army, navy, and air force show their strength by performing different dances on Republic Day.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "On Gandhi Jayanti, people offer tribute and prayers to remember his great achievements.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
